<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE rfc SYSTEM "rfc2629.dtd" []>
<?rfc toc="yes"?>
<?rfc symrefs="yes"?>
<?rfc compact="yes"?>
<?rfc subcompact="no"?>
<?rfc strict="no"?>
<?rfc rfcedstyle="yes"?>
<?rfc comments="yes"?>
<?rfc inline="yes"?>

<rfc category="bcp" docName="draft-ietf-sidrops-rpkimaxlen-05" ipr="trust200902">
    <front>
        <title abbrev="RPKI maxLength">The Use of Maxlength in the RPKI</title>

        <author fullname="Yossi Gilad" initials="Y." surname="Gilad">
            <organization>Hebrew University of Jerusalem</organization>
            <address>
                <postal>
                    <street>Rothburg Family Buildings, Edmond J. Safra Campus</street>
                    <city>Jerusalem</city>
                    <region></region>
                    <code>9190416</code>
                    <country>Israel</country>
                </postal>
                <email>yossigi@cs.huji.ac.il</email>
            </address>
        </author>

        <author fullname="Sharon Goldberg" initials="S." surname="Goldberg">
            <organization>Boston University</organization>
            <address>
                <postal>
                    <street>111 Cummington St, MCS135</street>
                    <city>Boston</city>
                    <region>MA</region>
                    <code>02215</code>
                    <country>USA</country>
                </postal>
                <email>goldbe@cs.bu.edu</email>
            </address>
        </author>

        <author fullname="Kotikalapudi Sriram" initials="K." surname="Sriram">
            <organization abbrev="USA NIST">USA National Institute of Standards and Technology</organization>
            <address>
                <postal>
                    <street>100 Bureau Drive</street>
                    <city>Gaithersburg</city>
                    <region>MD</region>
                    <code>20899</code>
                    <country>USA</country>
                </postal>
                <email>kotikalapudi.sriram@nist.gov</email>
            </address>
        </author>

        <author fullname="Job Snijders" initials="J." surname="Snijders">
            <organization abbrev="NTT">NTT Communications</organization>
            <address>
                <postal>
                    <street>Theodorus Majofskistraat 100</street>
                    <code>1065 SZ</code>
                    <city>Amsterdam</city>
                    <country>The Netherlands</country>
                </postal>
                <email>job@ntt.net</email>
            </address>
        </author>

        <author fullname="Ben Maddison" initials="B." surname="Maddison">
            <organization>Workonline Communications</organization>
            <address>
                <postal>
                    <street>114 West St</street>
                    <city>Johannesburg</city>
                    <code>2196</code>
                    <country>South Africa</country>
                </postal>
                <email>benm@workonline.africa</email>
            </address>
        </author>

        <date />

        <!-- <workgroup></workgroup> -->

        <keyword>Secure Internet routing</keyword>
        <keyword>Resource public key infrastructure</keyword>

        <abstract>

            <t>
                This document recommends ways to reduce forged-origin hijack attack surface by
                prudently limiting the set of IP prefixes that are included in a Route Origin
                Authorization (ROA). One recommendation is to avoid using the maxLength attribute
                in ROAs except in some specific cases. The recommendations complement and extend
                those in RFC 7115. The document also discusses creation of ROAs for facilitating
                the use of Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) mitigation services. Considerations
                related to ROAs and origin validation in the context of destination-based Remote
                Triggered Black Hole (RTBH) filtering are also highlighted.
            </t>

        </abstract>

    </front>

    <middle>
        <section title="Introduction" anchor="intro">
            <t>
                The RPKI <xref target="RFC6480"/> uses Route Origin Authorizations (ROAs) to create
                a cryptographically verifiable mapping from an IP prefix to a set of autonomous
                systems (ASes) that are authorized to originate that prefix.
                Each ROA contains a set of IP prefixes, and an AS number of an AS authorized to
                originate all the IP prefixes in the set <xref target="RFC6482"/>.
                The ROA is cryptographically signed by the party that holds a certificate for the
                set of IP prefixes.
            </t>

            <t>
                The ROA format also supports a maxLength attribute. According to
                <xref target="RFC6482"/>, "When present, the maxLength specifies the maximum length
                of the IP address prefix that the AS is authorized to advertise."
                Thus, rather than requiring the ROA to list each prefix the AS is authorized to
                originate, the maxLength attribute provides a shorthand that authorizes an AS to
                originate a set of IP prefixes.
            </t>

            <t>
                However, measurements of current RPKI deployments have found that use of the
                maxLength in ROAs tends to lead to security problems.
                Specifically, measurements have shown that 84% of the prefixes specified in ROAs
                that use the maxLength attribute, are vulnerable to a forged-origin subprefix
                hijack <xref target="HARMFUL" />.
                The forged-origin prefix or subprefix hijack involves inserting the legitimate AS 
                as specified in the ROA) as the origin AS in the AS_PATH, and can be launched
                against any IP prefix/subprefix that has a ROA. Consider a prefix/subprefix that
                has a ROA but is unused, i.e., not announced in BGP by a legitimate AS. A forged
                origin hijack involving such a prefix/subprefix can propagate widely throughout the
                Internet. On the other hand, if the prefix/subprefix were announced by the
                legitimate AS, then the propagation of the forged-origin hijack is somewhat limited
                because of its increased AS_PATH length relative to the legitimate announcement. Of
                course, forged-origin hijacks are harmful in both cases but the extent of harm is
                greater for unannounced prefixes.
            </t>

            <t>
                For this reason, this document recommends that, whenever possible, operators SHOULD
                use "minimal ROAs" that authorize only those IP prefixes that are actually
                originated in BGP, and no other prefixes. Further, it recommends ways to reduce
                forged-origin attack surface by prudently limiting the address space that is
                included in Route Origin Authorizations (ROAs). One recommendation is to avoid
                using the maxLength attribute in ROAs except in some specific cases. The
                recommendations complement and extend those in <xref target="RFC7115"/>. The
                document also discusses creation of ROAs for facilitating the use of Distributed
                Denial of Service (DDoS) mitigation services. Considerations related to ROAs and
                origin validation in the context of destination-based Remote Triggered Black Hole 
                RTBH) filtering are also highlighted.
            </t>
            <t>
                One ideal place to implement the ROA related recommendations is in the user
                interfaces for configuring ROAs. Thus, this document further recommends that
                designers and/or providers of such user interfaces SHOULD provide warnings to draw
                the user's attention to the risks of using the maxLength attribute.
            </t>
<!--
            <t>
                The recommendations in this document clarify and extend the following
                recommendation from <xref target="RFC7115"/>:
                <list>
                    <t>
                        One advantage of minimal ROA length is that the forged-origin attack does
                        not work for sub-prefixes that are not covered by overly long max length.
                        For example, if, instead of 10.0.0.0/16-24, one issues 10.0.0.0/16 and 10.0
                        42.0/24, a forged-origin attack cannot succeed against 10.0.666.0/24.
                        They must attack the whole /16, which is more likely to be noticed because
                        of its size.
                    </t>
                </list>
            </t>
-->

            <t>
                Best current practices described in this document require no changes to the RPKI
                specification and will not increase the number of signed ROAs in the RPKI, because
                ROAs already support lists of IP prefixes <xref target="RFC6482"/>.
            </t>

            <section title="Requirements">
                <t>
                    The key words "MUST", "MUST NOT", "REQUIRED", "SHALL", "SHALL NOT", "SHOULD", 
                    SHOULD NOT", "RECOMMENDED", "MAY", and "OPTIONAL" in this document are to be
                    interpreted as described in <xref target="RFC2119" />.
                </t>
            </section>

            <section title=" Documentation Prefixes">
                <t>
                    The documentation prefixes recommended in [RFC5737] are insufficient for use as
                    example prefixes in this document. Therefore, this document uses 
                    <xref target="RFC1918" /> address space for constructing example prefixes.
                </t>
            </section>

        </section>

        <section title="Suggested Reading">

            <t>
                It is assumed that the reader understands BGP <xref target="RFC4271"/>, RPKI
                <xref target="RFC6480"/>, Route Origin Authorizations (ROAs)
                <xref target="RFC6482"/>, RPKI-based Prefix Validation <xref target="RFC6811"/>,
                and BGPsec <xref target="RFC8205"/>.
            </t>

        </section>

        <section title="Forged-Origin Subprefix Hijack" anchor="hijack">

            <t>
                A detailed description and discussion of forged-origin subprefix hijacks are
                presented here, especially considering the case when the subprefix is not announced
                in BGP.
                The forged-origin subprefix hijack is relevant to a scenario in which:
                <list>
                    <t>
                        (1) the RPKI <xref target="RFC6480"/> is deployed, and
                    </t>
                    <t>
                        (2) routers use RPKI origin validation to drop invalid routes
                            <xref target="RFC6811" />, but
                    </t>
                    <t>
                        (3) BGPsec <xref target="RFC8205"/> (or any similar method to validate the
                            truthfulness of the BGP AS_PATH attribute) is not deployed.
                    </t>
                </list>
                Note that this set of assumptions accurately describes a substantial, and growing,
                number of large Internet networks at the time writing.
            </t>

            <t>
                The forged-origin subprefix hijack <xref target="RFC7115" />
                <xref target="GCHSS" /> is described here using a running example.
            </t>

            <t>
                Consider the IP prefix 192.168.0.0/16 which is allocated to an organization that
                also operates AS 64496.
                In BGP, AS 64496 originates the IP prefix 192.168.0.0/16 as well as its subprefix
                192.168.225.0/24.
                Therefore, the RPKI should contain a ROA authorizing AS 64496 to originate these
                two IP prefixes.
            </t>

            <t>
                Suppose, however, the organization issues and publishes a ROA including a maxLength
                value of 24:
                <list>
                    <t>
                        ROA:(192.168.0.0/16-24, AS 64496)
                    </t>
                </list>
                We refer to the above as a "loose ROA" since it authorizes AS 64496 to originate
                any subprefix of 192.168.0.0/16 up to and including length /24, rather than only
                those prefixes that are intended to be announced in BGP.
            </t>

            <t>
                Because AS 64496 only originates two prefixes in BGP: 192.168.0.0/16 and
                192.168.25.0/24, all other prefixes authorized by the "loose ROA" (for instance,
                192.168.0.0/24), are vulnerable to the following forged-origin subprefix hijack
                <xref target="RFC7115"/> <xref target="GCHSS" />:
                <list>
                    <t>
                        The hijacker AS 64511 sends a BGP announcement "192.168.0.0/24: AS 64511,
                        AS 64496", falsely claiming that AS 64511 is a neighbor of AS 64496 and
                        falsely claiming that AS 64496 originates the IP prefix 192.168.0.0/24.
                        In fact, the IP prefix 192.168.0.0/24 is not originated by AS 64496.
                    </t>
                    <t>
                        The hijacker's BGP announcement is valid according to the RPKI, since the
                        ROA (192.168.0.0/16-24, AS 64496) authorizes AS 64496 to originate BGP
                        routes for 192.168.0.0/24.
                    </t>
                    <t>
                        Because AS 64496 does not actually originate a route for 192.168.0.0/24,
                        the hijacker's route is the *only* route to the 192.168.0.0/24.
                        Longest-prefix-match routing ensures that the hijacker's route to the
                        subprefix 192.168.0.0/24 is always preferred over the legitimate route to
                        192.168.0.0/16 originated by AS 64496.
                    </t>
                </list>
                Thus, the hijacker's route propagates through the Internet, the traffic destined
                for IP addresses in 192.168.0.0/24 will be delivered to the hijacker.
            </t>

            <t>
                The forged-origin *subprefix* hijack would have failed if a "minimal ROA" described
                below was used instead of the "loose ROA".
                In this example, a "minimal ROA" would be:
                <list>
                    <t>
                        ROA:(192.168.0.0/16, 192.168.225.0/24, AS 64496)
                    </t>
                </list>
                This ROA is "minimal" because it includes only those IP prefixes that AS 64496
                originates in BGP, but no other IP prefixes <xref target="RFC6907" />.
            </t>

            <t>
                The "minimal ROA" renders AS 64511's BGP announcement invalid, because:
                <list>
                    <t>
                        (1) this ROA "covers" the attacker's announcement (since 192.168.0.0/24 is
                            a subprefix of 192.168.0.0/16), and
                    </t>
                    <t>
                        (2) there is no ROA "matching" the attacker's announcement (there is no ROA
                            for AS 64511 and IP prefix 192.168.0.0/24) <xref target="RFC6811" />.
                    </t>
                </list>
                If routers ignore invalid BGP announcements, the minimal ROA above ensures that the
                subprefix hijack will fail.
            </t>

            <t>
                Thus, if a "minimal ROA" had been used, the attacker would be forced to launch a
                forged-origin *prefix* hijack in order to attract traffic, as follows:
                <list>
                    <t>
                        The  hijacker AS 64511 sends a BGP announcement "192.168.0.0/16: AS 64511,
                        AS 64496", falsely claiming that AS 64511 is a neighbor of AS 64496.
                    </t>
                </list>
            </t>

            <t>
                This forged-origin *prefix* hijack is significantly less damaging than the
                forged-origin *subprefix* hijack:
                <list>
                    <t>
                        AS 64496 legitimately originates 192.168.0.0/16 in BGP, so the hijacker
                        AS 64511 is not presenting the *only* route to 192.168.0.0/16.
                    </t>
                    <t>
                        Moreover, the path originated by AS 64511 is one hop longer than the path
                        originated by the legitimate origin AS 64496.
                    </t>
                </list>
                As discussed in <xref target="LSG16"/>, this means that the hijacker will attract
                less traffic than he would have in the forged-origin *subprefix* hijack, where
                the hijacker presents the *only* route to the hijacked subprefix.
            </t>

            <t>
                In summary, a forged-origin subprefix hijack has the same impact as a regular
                subprefix hijack, despite the increased AS_PATH length of the illegitimate route.
                A forged-origin *subprefix* hijack is also more damaging than forged-origin
                *prefix* hijack.
            </t>

        </section>

        <section title="Measurements of Today's RPKI">

            <t>
                Network measurements have shown that 12% of the IP prefixes authorized in ROAs have
                a maxLength longer than their prefix length.
                The vast majority of these (84%) are vulnerable to forged-origin subprefix hijacks.
                These subprefixes are not announced in BGP by the legitimate AS. Even large
                providers are vulnerable to these attacks.
                See <xref target="GSG17"/> for details.
            </t>

            <t>
                These measurements suggest that operators commonly misconfigure the maxLength
                attribute, and unwittingly open themselves up to forged-origin subprefix hijacks.
                That is, they are exposing a much larger attack surface for forged-origin hijacks
                than necessary.
            </t>
        </section>

        <section title="Recommendations about Minimal ROAs and maxLength">

            <t>
                Operators SHOULD use "minimal ROAs" whenever possible.
                A minimal ROA contains only those IP prefixes that are actually originated by an AS
                in BGP, and no other IP prefixes.
                (See <xref target="hijack"/> for an example.)
            </t>

            <t>
                In general, except in some special cases, operators SHOULD avoid using the
                maxLength attribute in their ROAs, since its inclusion will usually make the ROA
                non-minimal.
            </t>

            <t>
                One such exception may be when all more specific prefixes permitted by the
                maxLength are actually announced by the AS in the ROA.
                Another exception is where: (a) the maxLength is substantially larger compared to
                the specified prefix length in the ROA, and (b) a large number of more specific
                prefixes in that range are announced by the AS in the ROA. This case should occur
                rarely in practice (if at all). Operator discretion is necessary in this case.
            </t>

            <t>
                This practice requires no changes to the RPKI specification and need not increase
                the number of signed ROAs in the RPKI, because ROAs already support lists of IP
                prefixes <xref target="RFC6482"/>.
                See also <xref target="GSG17"/> for further discussion of why this practice will
                have minimal impact on the performance of the RPKI ecosystem.
            </t>

            <section title="Creation of ROAs Facilitating DDoS Mitigation Service" anchor="nominimal">

                <t>
                    Sometimes, it is not possible to use a "minimal ROA", because an operator wants
                    to issue a ROA that includes an IP prefix that is sometimes (but not always)
                    originated in BGP.
                </t>

                <t>
                    In this case, the ROA SHOULD include (1) the set of IP prefixes that are always
                    originated in BGP, and (2) the set IP prefixes that are sometimes, but not
                    always, originated in BGP.
                    The ROA SHOULD NOT include any IP prefixes that the operator knows will not be
                    originated in BGP.
                    Whenever possible, the ROA SHOULD also avoid the use of the maxLength
                    attribute unless doing so has no impact on the set of included prefixes.
                </t>

                <t>
                    The running example is now extended to illustrate one situation where it is not
                    possible to issue a minimal ROA.
                </t>

                <t>
                    Consider the following scenario prior to deployment of RPKI.
                    Suppose AS 64496 announced 192.168.0.0/16 and has a contract with a Distributed
                    Denial of Service (DDoS) mitigation service provider that holds AS 64500.
                    Further, assume that the DDoS mitigation service contract applies to all IP
                    addresses covered by 192.168.0.0/22.
                    When a DDoS attack is detected and reported by AS 64496, AS 64500 immediately
                    originates 192.168.0.0/22, thus attracting all the DDoS traffic to itself.
                    The traffic is scrubbed at AS 64500 and then sent back to AS 64496 over a
                    backhaul data link.
                    Notice that, during a DDoS attack, the DDoS mitigation service provider AS
                    64500 originates a /22 prefix that is longer than AS 64496's /16 prefix, and so
                    all the traffic (destined to addresses in 192.168.0.0/22) that normally goes to
                    AS 64496 goes to AS 64500 instead.
                </t>

                <t>
                    First, suppose the RPKI only had the minimal ROA for AS 64496, as described
                    in <xref target="hijack"/>.
                    But if there is no ROA authorizing AS 64500 to announce the /22 prefix, then
                    the DDoS mitigation (and traffic scrubbing) scheme would not work.
                    That is, if AS 64500 originates the /22 prefix in BGP during DDoS attacks, the
                    announcement would be invalid <xref target="RFC6811" />.
                </t>

                <t>
                    Therefore, the RPKI should have two ROAs: one for AS 64496 and one for AS
                    64500.
                    <list>
                        <t>
                            ROA:(192.168.0.0/16, 192.168.225.0/24, AS 64496)
                        </t>
                        <t>
                            ROA:(192.168.0.0/22, AS 64500)
                        </t>
                    </list>
                    Neither ROA uses the maxLength attribute.
                    But the second ROA is not "minimal" because it contains a /22 prefix that is
                    not originated by anyone in BGP during normal operations.
                    The /22 prefix is only originated by AS 64500 as part of its DDoS mitigation
                    service during a DDoS attack.
                </t>

                <t>
                    Notice, however, that this scheme does not come without risks.
                    Namely, all IP addresses in 192.168.0.0/22 are vulnerable to a forged-origin
                    subprefix hijack during normal operations, when the /22 prefix is not
                    originated.
                    (The hijacker AS 64511 would send the BGP announcement "192.168.0.0/22: 
                    AS 6451, AS 64500", falsely claiming that AS 64511 is a neighbor of AS 64500
                    and falsely claiming that AS 64500 originates 192.168.0.0/22.)
                </t>

                <t>
                    In some situations, the DDoS mitigation service at AS 64500 might want to limit
                    the amount of DDoS traffic that it attracts and scrubs.
                    Suppose that a DDoS attack only targets IP addresses in 192.168.0.0/24.
                    Then, the DDoS mitigation service at AS 64500 only wants to attract the traffic
                    designated for the /24 prefix that is under attack, but not the entire /22
                    prefix.
                    To allow for this, the RPKI should have two ROAs: one for AS 64496 and one for
                    AS 64500.
                    <list>
                        <t>
                            ROA:(192.168.0.0/16, 192.168.225.0/24, AS 64496)
                        </t>
                        <t>
                            ROA:(192.168.0.0/22-24, AS 64500)
                        </t>
                    </list>
                </t>
                <t>
                    The second ROA uses the maxLength attribute because it is designed to
                    explicitly enable AS 64500 to originate *any* /24 subprefix of 192.168.0.0/22.
                </t>
                <t>
                    As before, the second ROA is not "minimal" because it contains prefixes that
                    are not originated by anyone in BGP during normal operations.
                    As before, all IP addresses in 192.168.0.0/22 are vulnerable to a forged-origin
                    subprefix hijack during normal operations, when the /22 prefix is not
                    originated.
                </t>
                <t>
                    The use of maxLength in this second ROA also comes with an additional risk.
                    While it permits the DDoS mitigation service at AS 64500 to originate prefix
                    192.168.0.0/24 during a DDoS attack in that space, it also makes the  *other*
                    /24 prefixes covered by the /22 prefix (i.e., 192.168.1.0/24, 192.168.2.0/24,
                    192.168.3.0/24) vulnerable to a forged-origin subprefix attacks.
                </t>
                <t>
                    There is another entirely different way of managing ROAs for DDoS mitigation
                    service.
                    In this scheme, ROAs are not pre-created for the DDoS mitigation service but
                    are created on the fly when the DDoS mitigation service request is made.
                    Further, the BGP announcements for actuating the DDoS mitigation service will
                    not be made until the ROAs propagate fully through the RPKI system.
                    Hence, there would be a latency involved in DDoS mitigation service going into
                    effect.
                    This method would be effective only if the latency is guaranteed to be within
                    some acceptable limit.
                    This calls for mechanisms to be in place for RPKI data propagation to occur
                    very fast.
                    Thus, this scheme of managing ROAs for DDoS mitigation service helps with
                    eliminating the attack surface for prefixes requiring this service.
                    However, the viability of this scheme depends on future work related to
                    achieving fast ROA propagation in the global RPKI system.
                </t>
            </section>
    </section>

    <section title="ROAs and Origin Validation for RTBH Filtering Scenario" anchor="rtbh">
        <t>
            Considerations related to ROAs and origin validation <xref target="RFC6811"/> for the
            case of destination-based Remote Triggered Black Hole (RTBH) filtering are addressed
            here.
            In RTBH filtering, highly specific prefixes (greater than /24 in IPv4 and greater than
            /48 in IPv6; possibly even /32 (IPv4) and /128 (IPv6)) are announced in BGP.
            These announcements are tagged with a BLACKHOLE Community <xref target="RFC7999"/>.
            It is obviously not desirable to use large maxlength or include any such highly
            specific prefixes in the ROAs to accommodate destination-based RTBH filtering.
            Therefore, operators SHOULD accommodate this scenario by accepting BGP announcements
            tagged with BLACKHOLE Community only if the following conditions are met:
            <list>
                <t>
                    (1) the announcement is received on a BGP session on which there is agreement
                        to accept BLACKHOLE Community, and
                </t>
                <t>
                    (2) the origin AS number in the announcement matches the neighbor (customer) AS
                        number associated with the BGP session, and
                </t>
                <t>
                    (3) the prefix in the announcement is subsumed by a less-specific prefix that
                    the neighbor (customer) AS is authorized to announce per RPKI/ROA.
                </t>
            </list>
            Additional details can be found in Section 5.5 in [NIST-800-189].
        </t>
    </section>

        <section anchor="Acknowledgments" title="Acknowledgments">
            <t>
                The authors would like to thank the following people for their review and
                contributions to this document: Omar Sagga (Boston University) and Aris
                Lambrianidis (AMS-IX). Thanks are also due to Matthias Waehlisch (Free University
                of Berlin) for comments and suggestions.
            </t>
        </section>

    </middle>

    <back>
        <!-- References Section -->

<!--
     Section 4.7f of [RFC2223bis] specifies the requirements for the
     references sections.  In particular, there MUST be separate lists of
     normative and informative references, each in a separate section.
     The style SHOULD follow that of recently published RFCs.

     In general, each normative reference SHOULD reference the most recent
     version of the specification in question.
-->

    <references title="Normative References">
        <?rfc include="reference.RFC.1918.xml"?>
        <?rfc include="reference.RFC.2119.xml"?>
        <?rfc include="reference.RFC.4271.xml"?>
        <?rfc include="reference.RFC.6480.xml"?>
        <?rfc include="reference.RFC.6482.xml"?>
        <?rfc include="reference.RFC.6811.xml"?>

    </references>

    <references title="Informative References">

        <reference anchor="GSG17" target="https://eprint.iacr.org/2016/1015.pdf">
            <front>
                <title>Maxlength Considered Harmful to the RPKI</title>
                <author initials="Y." surname="Gilad"><organization /></author>
                <author initials="O." surname="Sagga"><organization /></author>
                <author initials="S." surname="Goldberg"><organization /></author>
                <date year="2017" month="December" />
            </front>
            <seriesInfo name="in" value="ACM CoNEXT 2017" />
        </reference>

        <reference anchor="LSG16" target="http://cacm.acm.org/magazines/2016/10/207763-rethinking-security-for-internet-routing/">
            <front>
                <title>Rethinking Security for Internet Routing</title>
                <author initials="R." surname="Lychev"><organization /></author>
                <author initials="M." surname="Shapira"><organization /></author>
                <author initials="S." surname="Goldberg"><organization /></author>
                <date year="2016" month="October" />
            </front>
            <seriesInfo name="in" value="Communications of the ACM" />
        </reference>

        <reference anchor="GCHSS" target="https://eprint.iacr.org/2016/1010.pdf">
            <front>
                <title>Are We There Yet? On RPKI&#39;s Deployment and Security</title>
                <author initials="Y." surname="Gilad"><organization /></author>
                <author initials="A." surname="Cohen"><organization /></author>
                <author initials="A." surname="Herzberg"><organization /></author>
                <author initials="M." surname="Schapira"><organization /></author>
                <author initials="H." surname="Shulman"><organization /></author>
                <date year="2017" month="February" />
            </front>
            <seriesInfo name="in" value="NDSS 2017" />
        </reference>

        <reference anchor="HARMFUL" target="https://eprint.iacr.org/2016/1015.pdf">
            <!-- https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?doid=3143361.3143363 -->
            <front>
                <title>MaxLength Considered Harmful to the RPKI</title>
                <author initials="Y." surname="Gilad"><organization /></author>
                <author initials="O." surname="Sagga"><organization /></author>
                <author initials="S." surname="Goldberg"><organization /></author>
                <date year="2017" />
            </front>
            <!-- <seriesInfo name="in" value="NDSS 2017" /> -->
        </reference>

        <reference anchor="NIST-800-189" target="https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/SpecialPublications/NIST.SP.800-189.pdf">
            
            <front>
                <title>Resilient Interdomain Traffic Exchange: BGP Security and DDoS Mitigation</title>
                <author initials="K." surname="Sriram"><organization /></author>
                <author initials="D." surname="Montgomery"><organization /></author>
               
                <date year="December 2019" />
            </front>
            <seriesInfo name="NIST Special Publication," value="NIST SP 800-189" />
        </reference>




        <?rfc include="reference.RFC.6907.xml"?>
        <?rfc include="reference.RFC.7115.xml"?>
        <?rfc include="reference.RFC.7999.xml"?>
        <?rfc include="reference.RFC.8205.xml"?>
    </references>

</back>
</rfc>
<!-- vim: et ts=4 sts=4 sw=4 colorcolumn=100 spell :
-->
